MichelleFullwood

about

Cambridge, MA maf@mit.edu www.mit.edu/~maf github.com/michelleful

programming

Python, Django, Flask JavaScript, jQuery R, Scala, Matlab SQL, git

languages

native English advanced French Mandarin intermediate Arabic elementary Japanese Hungarian

awards

National Science Foundation
2011 NSF Graduate
Research Fellowship
Cornell University
2004 Merrill Scholar
2001 College Scholar
2000 Dean's Scholar
2002, 2004 Achievement
Awards in Arabic
2000–2004 Dean's List
Government of Singapore
2000 PSC Overseas
Merit Scholarship

community involvement

Event organizer & tutor
PyLadies Boston
Speaker
Boston Python
PyLadies Boston
lightning talk PyCon 2014

summary

Available September 2015. Computational linguist with 10 years' programming experience. Background in speech & natural language processing and full-stack web development.

education

since 2010 Ph.D. program in Linguistics, Massachusetts Institute of Technology

- · Research on problems in computational morphology and formal phonology
- · Coursework in linguistics, statistics, and machine learning
- · Teaching assistant in introductory linguistics and phonology

2000–2004 B.A. in Linguistics and Mathematics, Cornell University

- · Graduated magna cum laude and with distinction in all subjects, 4.0 GPA
- · Study abroad, Fall 2003: Budapest Semesters in Mathematics

ongoing edX and Coursera MOOCs

- ·edX: 6.SFMx Street Fighting Math, 11.132x Design & Dev of edTech
- · Crs: Functional Programming in Scala, JHU Data Science sequence (5/9)

experience

2008–2010 Web Developer, Imperial Consulting

· Developed custom web applications, front and back end, in Python, Django and jQuery, for clients in education, biomedical and finance industries

2008–2009 External Consultant, Centre for Strategic Infocomm Technologies

· Advised client on evaluation procedures in speech and text processing

2004–2008 R&D Engineer, later Consultant,

Centre for Strategic Infocomm Technologies

· Researched techniques and built engines for speech recognition, language and speaker identification, and cross-language information retrieval

· Managed projects to evaluate and acquire systems

2004 Summer Intern, PARC Palo Alto, C.

- · Engineered a computational Lexical Functional Grammar to cover the basic sentence constructions of Modern Standard Arabic
- · Built a root-and-pattern-based finite state Arabic morphological analyzer

projects

since 2012 Bayesian inference of non-concatenative morphology MI

- Extended state-of-the-art Bayesian techniques for morphological learning to the more complex case of non-concatenative morphology (Arabic, Hebrew)
- · Wrote a Markov Chain Monte Carlo (MCMC) sampler in Python to perform inference on a probabilistic model of non-concatenative morphology

2014 Fuzzy Arabic Dictionary

fuzzyarabic.herokuapp.com

Boston, MA

Singapore

· Developed a novel Arabic learners' dictionary that can be queried via non-exact transliteration

2014 Stressifier

 \cdot Developed an English learning aid that highlights stressed syllables in

user-input sentences.